(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
5th Gen アイドル衣装
5th Gen Idol Costume
イェーイみんな！見えてるー？
Yay everyone! Can you see us?
位置に戻れ！
Back to your positions!
なげえわ！
That was long!
えっ何今の？
Wait, what was that?
ということで、じゃあ自己紹介していきましょうか！
So, let's introduce ourselves!
はーい！
Okay!
はい、ねぽらぼの『ね』担当さんは？
Alright, NePoLaBo's 'Ne' representative?
はーい！ホロライブ5期生オレンジ担当…
Hi! Hololive 5th Gen's orange representative...
…アイドルVTuberの桃鈴ねねでーす！
...idol VTuber, Momosuzu Nene!
今日はよろしく！次に、ねぽらぼの…
Nice to meet you today! Next, NePoLaBo's...
…『ぽ』！
...'Po'!
ぽ！はーい！ねぽらぼの『ぽ』担当、尾丸ポルカです！
Po! Hi! NePoLaBo's 'Po' representative, Omaru Polka!
今日はよろしく！お願いします！イェーイ！
Nice to meet you today! Let's go! Yay!
ら！
La!
はーい！ねぽらぼの『ら』担当、雪花ラミィです！
Hi! NePoLaBo's 'La' representative, Yukihana Lamy!
みんなー！イェーイ！ら、イェーイ！
Everyone! Yay! La, yay!
そして、ぼ！はーい！ねぽらぼの…
And, Bo! Hi! NePoLaBo's...
…『ぼ』担当、獅白ぼたんでーす！イェーイ！
...'Bo' representative, Shishiro Botan! Yay!
はい、良かったね！お披露目！
Alright, that was great! The reveal!
おめでとうございました！凄かったね！
Congratulations! That was amazing!
どうでした？
How was it?
みんな、どうだった？
Everyone, what did you think?
あ、ね、コメント見る？コメント見る？
Ah, hey, should we check the comments? Check the comments?
全部で『良かった』って言ってるよ、絶対！
Everyone's definitely saying 'it was great'!
本当？
Really?
拍手だね、みんなね。拍手ばっかり！
It's all applause, everyone. Just applause!
拍手が多い！
Lots of clapping!
コメントが遅れてるのかな？拍手が多い…
Is the chat lagging? So many claps...
あ、良かったよ！最高だった！可愛かったって！
Ah, it's there! 'It was great!', 'The best!', 'So cute!'
本当？ありがとう！
Really? Thank you!
どう？なんかやっぱりリスナーの皆さん…
So? I wonder, for the listeners...
…どのアイドルタイプの服を着るかとか…
...what kind of idol outfit we'd wear...
そうそう、予想してたと思う。どうだった？予想とは。
Yeah, they were probably guessing. How was it compared to your guesses?
イメージとどう？当たったかな？
How's the image? Did anyone get it right?
当たってた？
Did you guess right?
ちなみに、ほら、色も同じなんじゃない？
By the way, look, aren't the colors the same?
あ、そうだよね！
Ah, you're right!
そう、この二人！この二人！
Yes, these two! These two!
ねっ、ねっこるじゃん！
See, it's 'Ne-Ko' (Nene-Polka)!
そうなの！
That's right!
しかも二人一緒に！
And the two of them together!
いや、抱きつくとか言うな！
Hey, don't say 'hugging'!
紐でしばらないで！
Don't tie us with a rope!
縛り付けて、無理やり連れてきてやったわ！
I tied her up and dragged her here by force!
すげえ。すげえな。
Amazing. That's something.
ちなみにこれは先輩で言うとどの先輩と同じタイプなの、これは？
By the way, which senior's outfit is this the same type as?
自分は、まずは、そら先輩とお揃い！
For me, first of all, it matches Sora-senpai!
あー！ちょっとね、恐れ多いな、なんか。
Ah! It's a bit intimidating, somehow.
ポルカね！私は何だろう。あ、4期生で言うと…
Polka, right! For me, what is it? Ah, in the 4th Gen...
…かなたんとかが出てくるし…
...it's like Kanata-chan...
そうそう、このパンツのイメージすごい強いって言われない？
Yeah, don't people say this pants image is really strong?
はいはい、確かに！
Yes, true!
あと、AZKi先輩とかも、色違いで一緒だよね！
Also, AZKi-senpai has the same one but in a different color!
あー、なるほどね！
Ah, I see!
ししろんは？ししろんはどの先輩と同じタイプなのかな？
What about Shishiron? What senior type is Shishiron?
私は、ノエル先輩、マリン先輩…
I'm Noel-senpai, Marine-senpai...
…あとわためとスバル先輩！
...also Watame and Subaru-senpai!
あ、ししわたじゃん！
Ah, it's Shishi-Wata!
そう、ししわたこれよね！え、凄い凄い。ちょっと両手上げて欲しいな。
Yeah, this is Shishi-Wata! Hey, amazing. I want you to lift both arms.
何で？
Why?
最高だよ！あとね、チョコ先生ともお揃いだけな、これ凄い！
It's the best! Also, it matches Choco-sensei! This is great!
何でそれ両手上げさせた？
Why did you make me lift both arms?
あれなんだよね、比較的、お胸の大きい先輩たちが着てるタイプの…
It's that type that, relatively, seniors with large chests wear...
…衣装の形なんだよね！
...that costume shape!
ワッショイしてるだけ！いやいいぞ！おへそと脇を同時に鑑賞できるな、素晴らしい！
It's a celebration! No, this is good! We can admire the navel and armpits at the same time, wonderful!
ししろん今日テンション高いね！
Shishiron, you're so energetic today!
いや、嬉しいじゃん！
I mean, I'm happy!
なんかね、ねぽらぼで揃ってアイドル衣装はやっぱ嬉しいじゃん！
Having matching idol outfits with NePoLaBo is really happy, after all!
乗り遅れに感動してたのに、今ししろ見て、俺全然違うわ！はーい！
I was moved by her getting on board, but now looking at Shishiro, it's totally different! Hi!
じゃあ、ラミィちゃんは？
So, how about Lamy-chan?
ラミィはね、みこ先輩とかはあちゃまとか、ころね先輩とかぺこら先輩とか…
Lamy is Miko-senpai, Haachama, Korone-senpai, Pekora-senpai...
…と同じタイプのかたちになってます！
...the same type of shape as them!
いいぞ！飛び跳ねて欲しい！飛び跳ねて欲しい！
Nice! I want you to jump! I want you to jump!
何で？さっきもやってたじゃん、そのくだり！
Why? We just did that whole routine!
マリン先輩と同じこと言ってんじゃん！
You're saying the same thing as Marine-senpai!
いや、何回見てもいい！もっともっと飛んで欲しい！
No, it's good no matter how many times I see it! I want you to jump more and more!
何で？自分が見たいだけだろ！ちょっと！
Why? You just want to see it yourself! Hey!
飛ぶね、飛ぶね、飛ぶ！
She's jumping, she's jumping, jump!
ねえ！やめて！
Hey! Stop it!
ししろ先輩！ねぇねぇ！
Shishiro-senpai! Hey, hey!
ほら！君あんなに「アイドル衣装が～」とかって昨日配信してたのに、これでもう...
Look! You were streaming yesterday like "Idol outfits are...", and now already...
もうはやだよ！あ、でもね、本当にね、あのほら...
It's already over! Ah, but really, you know, like...
お披露目の、あのサイン書くやつ！
The reveal, that part where we wrote our signatures!
え、すごかったよね！画面に書いてたんでしょ？
Eh, it was amazing, wasn't it! You were writing on the screen, right?
とってもね、ねねがね、自分に...
Very much, Nene, for herself...
あの都合のいい向きで書いてたからね、みんなには...
She wrote it in a direction convenient for her, so for everyone...
逆向きで見えてたっていうハプニングね！
it appeared backwards - what a mishap!
結構さ、今日何やるかってさ、お互い言わなかったじゃん？
Actually, we didn't tell each other what we were doing today, did we?
あ、そうだね！
Ah, that's right!
だから、さっき、えっ！
So, just now, I was like "Eh!"
え、でもいっぱい出しちゃったけど...
Eh, but we put out so much...
え、でもそれはそれで、なんか味があるっていうか...
Eh, but that has its own charm, or rather...
私たちらしくて良かった！あ、すごい良かった！
It was very "us", which was good! Ah, it was great!
まあ良かった。いいなと思った。なんかすごい演出が斬新だった。そうだね。
Well, it was good. I liked it. The production was really novel. True.
ね、初めてのことながら。
Yeah, for a first time.
いや～、揃ったね！揃った！
Wow, we're all together! Together!
ね、あとおまるんのね、ねねを最初に...
Yeah, and Omarun, Nene at the start...
あの、倒して... あ、そうだわ！
um, taking her down... Ah, that's right!
あの、ファンタジーゲームね！そう、ファンタジーゲーム始まりました。
That fantasy game! Yeah, the fantasy game began.
ポルカ先輩っていうのが良かったね。
That "Polka-senpai" bit was good.
でもファンタジーゲームのナレーションやってる人かと思ったわ、私。
But I thought it was someone doing narration for a fantasy game.
ゲーム始まっちゃうよ！
The game's starting!
今回もご協力いただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for your cooperation this time as well.
目覚めたらアイドルだったね、ね。そう、目覚めたら、ここはステージっていうのがね。
When I woke up, I was an idol, right? Yeah, "When I woke up, this was the stage."
アイドルだから毒リンゴ効かんかったわ、っていうやつでしょ？
Since I'm an idol, the poison apple didn't work - that's the one, right?
そうそう。でも、VTuberだから毒リンゴは効かないですよね（笑）みたいな。
Right, right. But like, "Since I'm a VTuber, poison apples don't work, right? (laughs)".
確かに効かないね。
True, they don't work.
へ～。そっか。
Heh~. I see.
何？「へ～」じゃないんだわ。何これ。
What? Don't just say "Heh~". What is this?
ラミィがさ、なんか、あの着替えたのめちゃくちゃさ、綺麗だったね、ターン。ね、ターン！
Lamy, that part where she changed, her turn was incredibly beautiful. Yeah, the turn!
ひゅん！って. これこれこれこれ！
Hyun! This, this, this, this!
また謎技術が使われてたわ。
Yet another mysterious technology was used.
いや、後ろのリボン本当可愛い！可愛い！見て、後ろ見て！
The ribbon on the back is truly cute! Cute! Look, look at the back!
あ、後ろ見てもらおう。
Ah, let's show the back.
ほら、みんな、みんな後ろ向いてほら！
Look, everyone, everyone turn around!
じゃ～ん！ポルカとラミィのが逆になってんの。
Ta-da! Polka and Lamy's are reversed.
そう、色反転してんの。
Yeah, the colors are inverted.
そうでよ。
That's right.
ちょ、もうちょっと引きで、引きで撮ってください。引きで！
Wait, please take a wider shot. Wide shot!
イエーイ！自分でそれを言うのめちゃくちゃ面白い。
Yay! It's so funny saying that ourselves.
さあ、今日みんなテンション高いな。高い。いや、そりゃそうでしょ！
Boy, everyone's energy is high today. High. Well, of course it is!
そうだよ。高いです。
Exactly. It is high.
まずいな。でね、あと最後のししろんだよ。ありがとな。
Uh oh. And then, there's Shishiron at the end. Thanks.
最高だったよね！もう、うん、もうちょっとなんかね... 羽ばたいちゃった。
It was the best! Like, yeah, a little bit... I kind of took flight.
羽ばたいちゃった。でも空気！あれ空気だよね？
Took flight. But the air! That was air, right?
空気！すごかった！
Air! It was amazing!
マシュマロが中に入った空気、ちゃんと...
Air that had marshmallows inside, properly...
ちゃんと作りました！ふわふわ、ちゃんと自分で作りました。
I made it properly! It's fluffy, I made it myself.
いや本当にすごかった！めっちゃ可愛かった。
No, it was really incredible! So cute.
SSRBまさか焼かれると思わなかった。
I never thought SSRB would get burned.
思わなかった。でもいつも投げられたり、投げられたり...
Me neither. But they're always being thrown, thrown...
爆発してんのに、さらに焼かれるんだ、っていう。
They're already exploding, and now they're getting burned too.
あ、俺が焼かれ続けて。それでさ、100万人記念おめでとうございます！おめでとう！
Ah, I'll just keep being burned. Also, congratulations on 1 million subscribers! Congratulations!
あれ、全然知らなかったから、そうなんですよ。
That, I didn't know about it at all, so yeah.
え、超良いじゃん！と思って。まあ良かった。ぜひ後でチェックしてください。はーい！そっちも大チェック！
Eh, I thought it was super cool. Well, it was good. Please check it out later. Okay! Check that out too!
じゃあ、どうする？え、何がどうするの？
So, what should we do? Eh, what do you mean what should we do?
あとね、見て見て、ねねさ、オレンジかと思いきやピンクなの、ちょっと。あ、アピール入りました。
And look, look, Nene's... I thought it was orange but it's actually pink. Ah, she's showing off.
ねねのこの色って何色になるの？
What color would you call this of Nene's?
結構、ほら見て、足！足！そういえばみんな足も...
Quite... look, look, legs! Legs! Come to think of it, everyone's legs too...
足もほら！私の足ほら！いつもの。ほら良いよね、それ。
Legs too, look! Look at my legs! The usual. Look, that's good.
私はトランプの柄。
I have a playing card pattern.
ねねはね、桃の花と桃。
Nene has peach blossoms and peaches.
いいね、みんな結構、ほら、みんならしい感じで。違うんだよ。
Nice, everyone's got their own style. They're all different.
あ、で、服によって、こっちにさ、ついてるのも違うよね、確か。
Ah, and depending on the outfit, the side this is on is different too, I think.
私こっち。ラミィちゃんと一緒？
Mine's here. Same as Lamy-chan?
そうそうそう。ラミィと一緒。
Yes, yes, yes. Same as Lamy.
へ～、そうなんだ。おお、本当だ。ね、うちらこっちだもんね。一緒、一緒。
Heh~, I see. Oh, you're right. Yeah, ours is on this side. Same, same.
え、そこの太もものそこだけついてるの、ヤバいな。ちょ。
Eh, it's crazy how it's only attached to that part of the thigh. Wait.
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！特別に、ちょっと見ていいよ、ほら。ラミィ、ラミィ、ラミィ！
It's fine, it's fine! I'll let you take a special look, here. Lamy, Lamy, Lamy!
え、ちょっと何、何？
Eh, wait, what, what?
ねねも、ねね！ちょ、違うんだよな、それ。
Nene too, Nene! Wait, that's not right.
何それ、ロデオしてんの、な。
What is that, are you doing a rodeo?
これ絶対違うだろ、それは。
That's definitely wrong.
あ、腕についてるのもいいな、ししろん。
Ah, the one on the arm is nice too, Shishiron.
腕は先輩みんなついてるんじゃないかな。
I think all the senpais have it on their arms.
あ、お揃いじゃないか、これ。
Ah, isn't this matching?
でね、耳がね、あれなんだよね。リボン！リボン！めっちゃ可愛い！そう、耳。
And the ears, you know. Ribbon! Ribbon! So cute! Yeah, the ears.
え、耳、ぴこぴこ。ぴこぴこもだけどさ、このリボンがええやんな。
Eh, ears, twitching. The twitching is one thing, but this ribbon is great, isn't it.
そうなの。ね、ネックレスにもお揃いで。いいな。
That's right. And there's a matching one on the necklace. Nice.
あ、ていうかさ、なんか、そうやって見るとししろ本当にロリだな、やっぱり。嘘やん。
Ah, come to think of it, seeing you like that, Shishiro really is a loli after all. No way.
結構、Twitterとか見てても、ロリっていう... いつもほら、かっこいいからさ、衣装が。
Quite a lot on Twitter, the "loli" thing... Because usually, you see, her outfits are cool.
だから、今日このアイドル衣装を着た感じ、どんな感じになるのかすごい楽しみにしてるリスナーさんいっぱいいたけど。
So, there were lots of listeners really looking forward to seeing how she'd look in this idol outfit today.
みんな、どうだったかな。ね、どうですか。感想またちょっとね、#ねぽらぼアイドル衣装 で、呟いてほしい。どうしたの？
Everyone, how was it? Well, what do you think? I want you to tweet your impressions with #NepolaboIdolOutfit. What happened?
どうしたの？もうなんか、集中切れちゃった？
What's wrong? Did you lose your concentration already?
集中切れちゃったのかな。さ、みんな、ちょっと、みんな今日ちょっと落ち着きない。
Maybe she lost her concentration. Now, everyone, a bit... everyone's a bit restless today.
だって嬉しいんだもん。着れてさ。イエーイ！
But we're happy. To be able to wear this. Yay!
フラメンコ！やめなさい、やめなさい。はあ、あっち。
Flamenco! Stop it, stop it. Phew, look over there.
ねえ、撮影とかしよっか。
Hey, shall we take some photos?
撮影会する！
Let's have a photo session!
誰か撮りたい人とかおる？
Is there anyone who wants to take them?
え、ねね持ちたい！
Oh, Nene wants to hold it!
持ちたい！
I want to hold it!
本当、おたまりやな。
You're really eager, aren't you?
じゃ、ねねがカメラ持って、みんなのこと撮ってみましょうか。
Then Nene will take the camera and try taking photos of everyone.
任せた！
We're counting on you!
いいよ。
Sure.
どんなふうに撮ってくれるの？
How are you going to take them?
ねね、なんかコメントも拾ってみようかな、なんかあったら。
Nene, I think I'll try picking up some comments too, if there are any.
あ、そう。
Ah, okay.
なんかあったら。
If there's anything.
どんなのがいい？
What kind would be good?
でもみんな可愛いしか言わない。
But everyone will only say "cute".
お、獅白のおへそ！
Oh, Shishiro's belly button!
うわ！ちょっと待って！やめて、そういうの！
Whoa! Wait a minute! Stop that kind of thing!
おいおいおい！
Hey, hey, hey!
欲望に忠実かよ！
You're so true to your desires!
獅白ガール！
Shishiro Girl!
獅白ガール。
Shishiro Girl.
お、いいの来た！
Oh, here comes a good one!
これ、これ！
This, this!
獅白の不意打ち！
Shishiro's surprise shot!
あ、いいね、この横。
Ah, nice, this side view.
もうちょっと、ラミ嬢ももうちょっとこっち。
A little more... Miss Lamy, a little more this way.
もうちょっと、お尻ぷりっと突き出して。
Stick your butt out a little more.
え、ちょっと！
Wait, what?!
お前、ちょっとカメラもうちょっと頑張れよ。
Hey, you, try a bit harder with the camera.
ダメ出しされてんじゃねえかよ。
You're being criticized, aren't you?
ちょっとねね！
Wait, Nene!
どうですか？
How's this?
画角、そうそうそう！そう！
The angle, yes, yes, yes! Like that!
もっと下からでもいいよ！
Even from lower down is fine!
あ、いいねいいね、撮っぴー！
Ah, nice, nice. Click!
よ、なんか厄介オタクさんみたいになってる！
Yo, you're like a troublesome fan!
違う違う違う！
No, no, no!
それ以上アイドルラインを超えないでっていう話！
I'm saying don't cross the idol line any further!
あ、そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
アイドルラインがあったか、一応。
There was an idol line, technically.
え、これすごい楽しいな、何これ！
Eh, this is so much fun, what's this!
おまるも、おまるも映って！
Omaru too, Omaru, get in the shot!
おまる映る。
Omaru's getting in.
おまるちゃん真ん中。
Omaru-chan in the middle.
はい、真ん中。
Yes, middle.
ポルカサンドしよう、ポルカサンド。
Let's do a Polka sandwich, Polka sandwich.
ポルカサンドする？
A Polka sandwich?
おまる、おまる、厚みが。
Omaru, Omaru... the thickness.
厚みが。
The thickness.
ないの？
There isn't any?
厚みがあんまりない！
There isn't much thickness!
何の厚みなんだよ！
Thickness of what?!
どんな感じ？
How is it?
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
It's good, it's good!
ナイス、ナイスポルカ！
Nice, nice Polka!
どんなポーズがいいかな？
What kind of pose would be good?
お顔、ちょっと。
Your face, a bit...
お顔ちょっと、あ、いいよ！
Your face a bit... ah, nice!
その困ってる感じのお顔！
That distressed-looking face!
お顔、ちょっと！
Your face, a bit!
困ってるポルカいいねえ。
Distressed Polka is nice.
お顔ちょっと、お顔ちょっと！
Your face a bit, your face a bit!
なんで捕まって、どうしたの？
Why are you caught? What happened?
どうしたの、大丈夫？
What happened? Are you okay?
いや、今日挙動がおかしい。
No, your behavior is weird today.
バグっちゃった。
It glitched.
はい、次。
Okay, next.
次の人、次の人！
Next person, next person!
誰、誰？
Who, who?
ぼたんも撮る？
Will Botan take some too?
あ、撮ろうか。
Ah, shall I take some?
あ、いいよ、ししろんも撮ろっか。
Ah, sure, let's have Shishiron take some too.
はい、じゃあどんなのがいい？
Okay, then what kind would be good?
ねねポルでなんかやる？
Shall we do something as Nene-Pol?
ねねポル？はい。
Nene-Pol? Okay.
何だこれ？
What is this?
何、何だこれ？
What... what is this?
何だよこれ、なちょか。
What is this? Let's see.
あ、背中合わせとかどう？
Ah, how about back-to-back?
背中合わせ、いいな。
Back-to-back, that's good.
同じ、同じ。
The same, the same.
あ、可愛い可愛い！
Ah, cute, cute!
可愛い！
Cute!
どう、どう？
How is it? How is it?
いいね、縦、すごい。
Nice, vertical, amazing.
あ、あ、あ、いいねいいね！
Ah, ah, ah, nice, nice!
これ横にしたらめちゃくちゃいい画角になる。
If you turn this horizontally, it'll be a great angle.
ちょっとちょっと、ふいふいさせない！
Wait, wait, don't let it sway!
ふいふいふい。
Sway, sway, sway.
あ、いいね、イエーイ。
Ah, nice, yay.
あ、いいね、可愛い！
Ah, nice, cute!
いいでしょ？
Good, right?
いいでしょ！
Isn't it good!
いいね！
Nice!
撮影楽しいね。
Taking photos is fun.
え、すごい可愛い。
Wow, so cute.
どうする、他に誰か持つ？
What should we do? Will anyone else hold it?
持ちたい人いる？
Is there anyone who wants to hold it?
え、なんか怖い。
Oh, I'm kind of nervous.
ドキドキしちゃう。
My heart is pounding.
じゃ、ラミも持ちたいよ。
Then, Lamy wants to hold it too.
え、何撮る？
Eh, what will you take?
ラミちゃん持つ？
Will Lamy-chan hold it?
あ、いいよ。
Ah, sure.
ラミちゃん持つ？
Will Lamy-chan hold it?
え、次は...
Eh, next is...
次はそうだね。
Next is, that's right.
次はお持ちや。
Next is holding it.
おっしゃ、じゃあちょっと3人並んでもらって。
Alright, then could you three line up for a bit?
はーい。
Oka~y.
あ、いいね、可愛い！
Ah, nice, cute!
あ、ちょっと逆がいいわ、逆。
Ah, wait, the opposite side would be better.
逆？
Opposite?
こっち、こっち、こっち。
This way, this way, this way.
あ、客席側！
Ah, the audience side!
なるほどね。
I see.
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
はい、もっとギュッとしてギュッとして集まって！
Okay, get closer together, closer together!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、いいね、可愛い！
Ah, nice, cute!
あ、あ、あ、あ！
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あ、イエーイ、いいね！
Ah, yay, nice!
あ、いいね、いいね。
Ah, nice, nice.
ちょっとね。
Just a bit.
イエーイ、お願いします。
Yay, please.
なんかソーシャルディスタンス。
Kind of like social distance.
ソーシャルディスタンスしてみて。
Try doing social distance.
中継に映ってきた人みたいになってる。
You look like people appearing in a live broadcast.
天気予報とかの後ろにいる人のやつだ。
It's like the people standing behind a weather report.
オッケーです。
Okay, that's good.
はい、可愛いですね。
Yes, you're cute.
さ、最後、ほらポルカも。
Now, lastly, look, Polka too.
ていうかさ、こんなんコメントするほうもさ。
By the way, for people commenting on this...
可愛いしか言えなくない？
Can they really say anything besides "cute"?
確かに思った。
I thought so too.
可愛いんだもん。
Because you're cute.
邪気ん、ポルカカメラ！
Shing! Polka camera!
ラミだ。
It's Lamy.
あれ、ラミだ。
Oh, it's Lamy.
あ、ししらみを撮る際は、ですね。
Ah, when taking photos of Shishi-Lami...
あ、いいね、ししらみを撮る際は。
Ah, nice, when taking photos of Shishi-Lami...
やっぱりさっきの斜め角度がマストなんですけど。
...that diagonal angle from earlier is a must.
ねえちゃんもおいで。
Nene-chan, you come too.
おいで。
Come here.
あれ、なんかいる。
Oh, someone's here.
ねえちゃんもおいで。
Nene-chan, you come too.
こういう感じっすね。
It's like this.
で、目線こっちください。
And please look this way.
はーい。
Oka~y.
で、あ、ね、ねねのポーズ、ちょっと何か何、しとやか。
And... oh, Nene's pose is a bit... what, graceful?
いつもと違う。
It's different from usual.
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
俺が多分斜めに撮るっていう確信して可愛い感じ。
You're probably confident that I'll take it diagonally and look cute.
あ、いいね、いいやん！
Ah, nice, that's good!
可愛いよ、いただきました、ありがとうございます。
You're cute. Got the shot, thank you.
ワーオ！
Wow!
すごいワーオ！
So wow!
プロだなあ。
Such a pro.
ローアングラーになっちゃった。
I've become a low-angle photographer.
やば。
Whoa.
腹筋ハンパな。
Your abs are incredible.
ねね、ほら、一番可愛いポーズ。
Nene, come on, your cutest pose.
はい！
Yes!
え、え、え？
Eh, eh, eh?
ファンサービスポーズ。
Fan service pose.
はい、イエーイ！
Yes, yay!
やめなさい。
Stop that.
なんかさ、ポルカさ。
You know, Polka...
ポルカさ、アイドルポーズができなかったから、ねねに教わろうと思ったけど、やめたわ。
Polka couldn't do an idol pose, so I thought I'd learn from Nene, but I changed my mind.
あ、ほんと。
Oh, really.
ラミ、アイドルポーズ。
Lamy, idol pose.
ほー！
Whoa!
美し獅白も並んで、ちょっとアイドルポーズのお手本見せて。
Beautiful Shishiro, line up too, and show us a model idol pose.
いいよ。
Sure.
今ねねが真ん中で謎のポーズしてる。
Now Nene is in the middle doing a mysterious pose.
え、え？
Eh, eh?
何だ、ねね。
What is it, Nene?
ねね教えて。
Tell us, Nene.
なに、そのねねのポーズは。
What's with that pose, Nene?
え、これっぽいでしょ、これっぽい。
Eh, it's like this, right? Like this.
こういうやつ。
This kind of thing.
あ、すごい、すごい！
Ah, amazing, amazing!
あ、いい、可愛い、これ！
Ah, nice, this is cute!
いいもみしだぽあ。
Nice Momishida-poa.
いただきました、はい、可愛い。
Got it, yes, cute.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
わかった。
Got it.
ラミの何、何だっけ。
Lamy's... what was it?
ちょっと4人でさ、やりたいな、ちょっと。
I want to do something with the four of us, just for a bit.
ラミの何、今のアイドルポーズ、せっかくだから。
Lamy's... since we're here, that idol pose from just now.
いいよ。
Sure.
こっちから行くの？
Are we going from this way?
ポルカ、ポルカ、ほらこっち、真ん中おいで、こっち。
Polka, Polka, look, this way, come to the middle, this way.
はい、なんか、ほら、ちょっとアイドルポーズしな、ほら。
Okay, come on, do some idol poses!
えっと、真ん中ら辺の人ってないですよね。
Um, the people in the middle don't have one, do they?
何してんの、お前らも、なんか、こういう原始的な感じがいいんじゃない？
What are you doing? Wouldn't something primitive like this be good?
原始的？
Primitive?
グー？いいわね、いいわね。あ、いいわね。
A fist? Nice, nice! Oh, that's good.
あ、でもさ、よくお前らこうやってやってんじゃん。
But you guys usually do this, don't you?
うん、でも真ん中だからさ。
Yeah, but since we're in the middle...
え、じゃあ端っこ行こうか。
Then let's go to the ends.
あ、やったー！
Oh, yay!
そっちのけでしてる、今。めっちゃ背伸びしてる。
They're totally ignoring us. They're really stretching.
こういう感じ？
Like this?
はっ！はっ！
Hah! Hah!
おいしょ！おいしょ！よしよしよし！よしよし！よしよし！
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Good, good, good! Nice, nice!
ポルカ、大丈夫？
Polka, are you okay?
何でそんな苦しそうなの？
Why do you look like you're in pain?
いや、分からん。
I don't even know.
ちょっと、何やってんだよ！
Hey, what are you doing!
え、なんだかんだで、でも、もうあれじゃね？
Wait, after all that, isn't it time?
え？あ、というわけで、ほら。
Eh? Oh, speaking of which, look.
もうそろそろね、私たちが集まった理由もあるでしょうに。
It's about time, there's a reason we all gathered here.
あ、そうですねー！
Ah, that's right!
この時間は一旦終わりです。
This segment is over for now.
えー！寂しいー！寂しい！
Ehh! So sad! So lonely!
みんな、あと1週間後に迫ったよ！
Everyone, it's coming up in just one week!
そうだお！
That's right!
いろいろあるでしょ？それを、おさらいしていきたいと思います！
There's a lot going on, right? Let's review everything!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ついに近づいた、あと1週間後かよ！
It's finally close, just one week away!
1週間後だよ！お楽しみですね！
One week left! Looking forward to it!
というわけで皆様、今週末！
So everyone, this weekend!
3月19日と20日、hololive SUPER EXPO 2022！うわー！
March 19th and 20th, hololive SUPER EXPO 2022! Whoa!
そして、hololive 3rd fes. Link Your Wish supported by ヴァイスシュヴァルツ、開催されます！
And, hololive 3rd fes. Link Your Wish supported by Bushiroad, will be held!
いぇーい！ふー！
Yay! Woo!
2022.3.19 (SAT) - 3.20 (SUN) in MAKUHARI MESSE EVENT HALL
現在、hololive 3rd fes. は、SPWN、ニコニコ動画で配信チケットを販売中になっております！
Currently, streaming tickets for hololive 3rd fes. are on sale on SPWN and Nico Nico Douga!
いぇーい！
Yay!
直前の購入だと、ちょっとサーバーが混雑しちゃったりするので、これマジで。
If you buy right before it starts, the server might get congested, so seriously.
本当にそう。本当にそう。
That's very true. Very true.
経験者は語る。早め、早めのご購入をお勧めします！
Spoken from experience. We recommend buying early!
お勧めしますー！
We recommend it!
そして次、ねぽらぼメンバーからは、DAY1！はい、ねね！ポルカ！
And next, from NePoLaBo, on DAY 1! Yes, Nene! Polka!
はい！はい！ああ、ねねじゃなかった！
Yes! Yes! Oh, I wasn't Nene!
DAY2！はい！はい、ラミィ、ぼたん！が出演します！
DAY 2! Yes! Lamy and Botan will be performing!
よろしくお願いします！
We look forward to seeing you!
で、ねぽらぼメンバー全員の頑張ってる姿が見たい人は通しチケットお勧めします！
And for those who want to see all of NePoLaBo doing their best, we recommend the 2-day pass!
お勧めしますー！
We recommend it!
今日、明日、配信終了後から1ヶ月まで。そのライブの配信終了後から1ヶ月までがアーカイブ見放題なんで、
From today, and tomorrow, until one month after the stream ends. You can watch the archive as much as you want for a month after the live,
何百回も見られちゃいます！
so you can watch it hundreds of times!
おー、やったー！
Oh, yay!
まあ、マスト、マスト。
It's a must, definitely a must.
今回のライブ、全編ARでのライブステージになってたり、生バンドでの演出だったり、
This live event will feature a full AR stage and performances with a live band,
hololive English, hololive Indonesiaのメンバーも参加したり、とにかく今までにない挑戦が盛りだくさんとなっております！
with members from hololive English and hololive Indonesia also participating. Anyway, it's packed with new challenges like never before!
繋がってるー！
We're all connected!
また、hololive 3rd fes. では、今日から、ん？配信リリースされている、
Also, at hololive 3rd fes., starting from today... huh? Being released digitally...
hololiveの新しい全体曲「Prism Melody」がライブ初お披露目されるそうです！うわー、すごい！
hololive's new group song "Prism Melody" will be performed for the first time! Wow, amazing!
あ、プリメロだー！
Oh, it's PriMelo!
これだこれだ、これ、これ！
This is it, this is it!
「Prism Melody」は、はい、hololive 3rd fes. のために作られた新曲となってるらしいよ！
Apparently "Prism Melody" is a new song made specifically for hololive 3rd fes.!
あ、ぜ、ねねちゃんおる！見て見て！ねねちゃんおるじゃん！
Oh, Nene-chan is there! Look, look! Nene-chan is in it!
そうなんです、ねね一緒に歌わせていただきましたー！
That's right, I got to sing it together with them!
うわー、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
どうだった、歌ってみて？
How was it, singing it?
いや、あのね、すごいキラキラアイドル曲、前向きって感じ。
Well, you know, it's a really sparkly idol song, very positive.
あの、とっても覚えやすくて、たぶんみんなもね、1回聴いたらね、
It's very catchy, so I think if everyone hears it once,
あのサビの「Prism Melody」のところはすごい頭に入ってくるんじゃないかなと思います！
the "Prism Melody" part in the chorus will really stick in your head!
これはね、ライブの前までに予習してもらって、ライブで一緒に盛り上がってもらおうということで。
So, we want you to practice it before the live so we can all get excited together.
そうそう、ペンライト振るタイミングとかあるかもね！
Right, there might be specific moments to wave your penlights!
これはね、ライブで定番曲になるんじゃないかなって感じがしたね。
I get the feeling this will become a staple song for the lives.
ねー、あとこの構成がガチで神！
And this composition is seriously divine!
最高です！
It's the best!
hololiveの歌うまたちが…そうなんだよ！素晴ら！素晴ら！
hololive's best singers... Exactly! Splendid! Splendid!
スバラ。スバラ。ねね、ねね。
Splendid. Splendid. Nene, Nene.
あと、はい、ライブといえば、グッズもあるよね！
Also, speaking of the live event, there are goods too!
そうだー！
That's right!
hololive 3rd fes. hololive SUPER EXPO では、ライブTシャツやペンライト、マフラータオルなどのライブの必須グッズがお買い求めいただけます！
At hololive 3rd fes. and hololive SUPER EXPO, you can buy essential live goods like T-shirts, penlights, and muffler towels!
必須アイテム！取ったスペシャルグッズも盛りだくさん！
Essential items! There are plenty of other special goods too!
なになに、どこで買えるの？っていう購入の詳細、こちら、物販レギュレーションもあるので、
Like, where can I buy them? For purchasing details and sales regulations,
EXPO 3rd fes. のhololiveのこちらホームページ、グッズページに書いてあります。ぜひチェックしてみてくださいね！
please check the goods page on the official hololive EXPO 3rd fes. website. Be sure to check it out!
チェックしてみてくださいねー！
Be sure to check it out!
そして今回、ペンライトの…
And this time, the penlight...
こちらご紹介してまいります。
We're going to introduce these.
ねねは何色ですか？
Nene, what's your color?
ねね、オレンジ！
Nene is orange!
ポルカは赤、レッド！
Polka is red, red!
ラミィはライトブルー。
Lamy is light blue.
そして獅白はホワイト。
And Shishiro is white.
今回の注目すべき点は...
The noteworthy point this time is...
見てください。なんか、あれ？
Look at this. Wait, what?
いっぱいあるな。
There's so many.
そう！今回はね、ENやIDのメンバーも...
Right! This time, EN and ID members...
みんなね、このライトの色が決まっておりますので。
...all have their light colors decided.
イナニスがバイオレットで、ムメイ先輩がパープル。
Ina'nis is violet, and Mumei-senpai is purple.
ここら辺の違い、なるほど、よく見ると違うんだね。
I see, so they're actually different when you look closely.
IDの皆さんも付いてるので、その辺りもチェックしてみてください。
The ID members are included too, so please check them out.
獅白のカラー珍しくない？
Isn't Shishiro's color unusual?
なんで？白だよ？
Why? It's white.
白、ノエル団長とね、二人だけなんだよ。
White, it's only me and Noel-danchou.
いいよね。すごい目立つから、白って色、目立つよな。
It's good. It really stands out. White is a prominent color.
ねねもさ、めっちゃ目立つよね、あの色。
Nene's color stands out a lot too.
オレンジも振ってほしい！
I want you to wave orange too!
ライトブルーも！
Light blue too!
両方持って振って、お願いします！
Hold both and wave them, please!
以上、盛りだくさんの情報をお送りさせていただきました！
That was a lot of information we've shared with you!
あと一週間です！
Only one week to go!
楽しみにしててほしい！
I hope you're looking forward to it!
そしてこの後はですね、公式ファンクラブでの、おまけ配信もあります！
And after this, we'll have a bonus stream on the official fan club!
公式ファンクラブでは、コメントのみんなのリクエストなんかにも...
In the official fan club stream, we'd like to take...
...ちょっとお答えしたいなと思っておりますので、お楽しみに！
...some requests from the comments, so look forward to it!
じゃあせっかくアイドル衣装でさ、ねぽらぼになっちゃったから...
Since we're in our idol outfits and we're NePoLaBo...
なんかちょっと一曲ぐらい歌いたいなと！
I feel like singing at least one song!
これになるとそれって言われるからさ。
When it comes to this, people always expect that one.
これってなっちゃうものがあるじゃん。
There's that one song that just fits.
ホロライブの楽曲の...
A Hololive song...
...全体曲の！
...a group song!
水飲むわ。
I'm gonna drink some water.
お水休憩入ります。
Taking a water break.
じゃあみんな、所定の位置について。
Okay everyone, get into position.
エンジン組むな？
Shall we do a huddle?
ねねさん、お願いします。
Nene-san, if you would.
それではみんな、アイドル衣装でのねぽらぼの第一歩...
Now everyone, NePoLaBo's first step in our idol outfits...
...踏み出していきましょう！
...let's take it together!
ねぽらぼ、ファイ、オー！
NePoLaBo, fight, oh!
夢見る空へ
To the Dreamy Sky
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Never let go of our joined hands
いくよ！
Here we go!
いこうよ！
Let's go!
夢見る空へ
To the dreamy sky
窓越しに見上げた
I looked up through the window
とても小さい
So very small...
夢見る空へ ここで出会えたのは
To the dreamy sky, where we met...
数えきれない奇跡
...is a countless miracle.
繰り返した一歩が
Each step we took repeatedly...
きらめきを繋いで
...connected the sparkles.
星のような笑顔
Smiles like stars...
導いた
...guided us.
Day by day みんなの声が力になる
Day by day, everyone's voices become our strength.
Step by step ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
Step by step, the things we each aim for here...
それぞれ描くもの
...the things we each envision...
それぞれ願った夢へ
...toward the dreams we each wished for.
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Our joined hands, we'll never let go.
一人一人違う色で描き出すときめき
The excitement we draw with each of our different colors.
振り向くことなくまっすぐに
Looking straight ahead without turning back.
行くよ！
Let's go!
行こう！夢見る空へ
Let's go! To the dreamy sky.
笑い合ったことや
The times we laughed together...
尽きそうにない話題
...and the topics that never seemed to end.
思い出いっぱいなのに
Even though there are so many memories...
あっという間の日々
...the days went by in a flash.
上書きじゃなくって
Not as an overwrite...
名前付けて保存
...but "Save As" with a name.
どれも全部大事って
Saying that every single one is important...
言い切れる
...I can say for sure.
One for all みんなのためが力になる
One for all, for everyone's sake becomes our strength.
All for one 共に賑やかすぎるくらい
All for one, together so lively it's almost too much...
笑顔がもう止まらない
...our smiles just won't stop.
思いは膨らんでいく
Our feelings keep growing.
重ねた今 ぎゅっと噛みしめた
The "now" we've layered, I'll cherish it deeply.
一人一人違う声で歌声は広がる
Our singing voices spread with each of our different voices.
風を感じたらまっすぐに
Once we feel the wind, we'll head straight on.
行くよ！
Let's go!
行こう！夢見る空へ
Let's go! To the dreamy sky.
憧れて手を伸ばし
Reaching out with admiration...
掴み取ったその光が
...that light we grasped...
いつの日か また誰かの憧れに
...will someday become someone else's admiration again.
変わる 繋げよう
It changes, let's pass it on.
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Our joined hands, we'll never let go.
一人一人違う色で描き出すときめき
The excitement we draw with each of our different colors.
出会った全てにありがとう
Thank you for everything we've encountered.
奇跡だって起こし続け
Continuing to make miracles happen...
ずっとずっとそばにいるよ
...I'll always, always be by your side.
行くよ！
Let's go!
行こう！夢見る空へ
Let's go! To the dreamy sky.
5th Gen アイドル衣装
5th Gen Idol Outfit